Julien Soulé

An enthusiast specialized in cross-platform mobile app development with Google's Flutter framework, solving real-world problems using engineering skills with passion for friendly software design, solid architecture, best practices and documentation.

hashirshoaeb@gmail.com (+92) 311-454-2616 Lahore, Pakistan linkedin.com/in/hashirshoaeb hashirshoaeb.github.io

EXPERIENCE

Manafa, Saudi Arabia — Software Engineer (Flutter)

JAN 2023 - PRESENT

- Architectured a scalable solution and successfully implemented support for multi-themes (light/dark) in the Sukuk app.
- Completed certification on the "Flutter and Firebase Masterclass," demonstrating proficiency in utilizing Flutter and Firebase technologies for app development.
- Tools: Flutter, Dart, Riverpod.

EMPGLabs, Lahore — Associate Software Engineer (iOS)

APR 2022 - JAN 2023

- Get the opportunity to learn native iOS development and architecture.
- Documented onboarding of freshie and open sourced my swift learning journey.
- Created an example project to fully explain VIP architecture.
- Took the initiative to identify, document and fix technical debt.
- Contributed in developing (instagram like) stories, and is expected to increase lead generation by 11%
- Tools: swift, Ulkit, SwiftUl.

Lessgo, UK — Software Engineer (Flutter)

DEC 2020 - APR 2022

- Contributed in releasing from MVP to version 3 of <u>Lessgo</u> A social networking app for social gathering.
- Participated in implementing major features of the app including (meetups, memories, clubs) creation, updation and deletion flow.
- Collaborated with the design team to come up with a design guideline that helped developers in writing a custom theme class for the app, that improved the consistent look and code reusability.
- Refactored the codebase and migrated the app to dart null-safety.
- Refactored models and implemented freezed to auto generate tedious methods.
- Got the opportunity to learn about app architecture, Bloc and other design patterns.
- Integrated <u>Gleap</u>(Bug Battle) for bug and crash reporting.
- Learned fastlane to automate the to automate the device registration for new iOS devices.
- In addition, being an open source enthusiast, I participated in reporting bugs to third party packages, and helped in resolving some of the issues by raising pull requests.
- I was mainly responsible for creating responsive screens, implementing new features, code refactoring and iOS bug fixes.
- Tools: Flutter, Dart, Bloc, Rxdart

EDUCATION

National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST), Islamabad — B.Eng

Bachelors in Computer Engineering

2016 - 2020

PROJECTS

QuranTalk — Emotional Well-being App

APR 2021

Created an app that provides a space for muslims around the world to improve their emotional and mental health. The app helps people to navigate their emotions in the light of the Quran. QuranTalk is available on both iOS and Android Stores. Also developed a landing page for it.

Tools: Flutter, Dart, html, css

StarBook — Mood Tracker & Journaling App

NOV 2020

Developed an open source digital diary and a *mood tracking app* that helps users in keeping track of their mood and productivity throughout the month or year.

- StarBook is my practice project that I created while learning Flutter.
- I preferred the MVC pattern as base architecture for the app.
- Taking some inspiration from Apple's UI. I learned Apple's Human Interface design guidelines and used the Cupertino
 package and theme to support light and dark mode.
- Used Hive DB for local storage.
- Sticked with setState and changeNotifier on purpose to learn the core apis for state management.

The app is available on the App Store. Also developed a landing page for it.

Tools: Flutter, Dart, Reactis.

<u>Portfolio</u> — Developer's Portfolio Website Template

MAY 2019

There are many portfolio website templates available on Github, however, I didn't find one that really suits my needs so I created this one. A simple, easy to configure, lightweight, and responsive static portfolio website template for developers and freelancers. Over 60+ people are using it.

- Taking from design to deployment, I firstly designed it on Figma and then took it to development using Next.js and Bootstrap5 and then automate the deployment using Github Actions.
- Project is open source under MIT license and has 90+ forks on Github

Tools: Nextjs, Bootstrap5, GitHub Actions

Home - Developer's Portfolio Website Template

MAY 2019

Created an open source *portfolio webpage* using Reactjs and GitHub APIs hosted over GitHub pages. Entire project was kept easy to configure and edit. Over *1200+* people are using it.

Tools: Reactis.

I FADERSHIP

TechTogether Miami — Mentor & Workshop Host

FEB 2022 - FEB 2022

- TechTogether Miami was an online hackathon that served 402 hackers in Feb, 2022, 56% of whom have never attended a hackathon before.
- I participated by hosting an "Introduction to Flutter" workshop at TechTogether Miami...
- Over 16 hackers attended the workshop.
- Workshop was critical in helping our hackers get the training they needed to build an awesome hack.

Script Winter of Code 2021 — Project Maintainer & Mentor

JAN 2021 - FEB 2021

- Script Winter Of Code is the 2 month long open source program by Script Foundation India.
- I led and mentored a group of 12 participants. Together we fixed 47 issues and added new features in 100+ commits to the StarBook project.
- As maintainer of the project I was responsible for managing tasks, assigning issues and reviewing pull requests
- I reviewed 50+ pull requests and merged 40.